roombookingsystem.co.uk 2018-12-30

# School Cloud Systems - Contact Us

#### Last Updated: 25th May 2018

This privacy notice applies to visitors to our website, or individuals who contact us by telephone, e-mail or other means (including other electronic means).

## Who we are

We are School Cloud Systems Ltd, a company registered in Scotland (company number SC366647) whose registered office is at The Albus, Brook Street, Glasgow, United Kingdom, G40 3AP.

We are a data controller for the purposes of the General Data Protection Regulation (Regulation (EU) 2016/679) and related data protection legislation with regard to personal data we collect if you visit our websites (as hosted on schoolcloudsystems.co.uk; roombookingsystem.co.uk; parentseveningsystem.co.uk; meettheteacher.com) (" **Website** ") or contact us by telephone, e-mail or other means (including other electronic means).

## How to contact us

If you have any questions about this privacy notice or our data protection policies generally, please contact us:

> By post: School Cloud Systems, The Albus, Glasgow, G40 3AP
> 
> By email: dataprotection@schoolcloudsystems.co.uk
> 
> By phone: 0333 344 3403

## Privacy notice

We are committed to protecting your personal data and your privacy. This privacy notice sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, or that we acquire from a third party, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

Before we process your personal data, we are obliged to inform you of who we are, why we need to process your personal data, what we will do with your personal data and to whom we will pass your personal data. 

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.

## Visitors to the Website

#### What information do we collect and process?

When you visit our Website or any other domain name registered in our name), we use Google Analytics to automatically collect information about your computer, including your IP address, information about your visit, your browsing history, and how you use our Website. We use cookies within our Website. You can read more about how we use cookies in the “ **Cookies** ” section below. Please note the Website is not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect personal data relating to children.

#### How is your information used?

We use your information collected automatically from our Website to improve the customer experience and functionality of our Website. 

We do not use such information for any form of automatic decision-making, including profiling.

#### With whom do we share your information?

We may use third parties to host or develop our Website, and these third parties will have access to your personal data that we store. The third parties we use are data processors and will only process your personal data on our instructions and subject to obligations of confidentiality.

#### Third-party websites

Our Website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.

#### Lawful processing

When we process your personal data for the purposes of hosting or improving our Website, we do so on the basis of our legitimate interests in maintaining a relevant and functioning website and improving customer experience.

## Cookies

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site.

We use temporary cookie files called session cookies which are erased when you close your browser.

You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of the Website may become inaccessible or not function properly.

## People who contact us

#### What information do we collect and process?

_Telephone -_ When you call us, we will collect your name and telephone number, and where relevant, we may collect other details including other contact details and information relating to any contract for products or services relating to you. Any call made to us may be monitored but will not be recorded.

_E-mail_ \- When you e-mail us, we will collect your name, e-mail address and the contents of your message and any attachments.

_Website contact -_ When you fill out any of the contact forms on the Website, we may collect:

  * Your name;
  * Your email address; and
  * Your phone number

_Post_ \- If you send us a letter or other correspondence by post, we will collect any personal data contained in such correspondence. We may scan and electronically store any letters or other correspondence we receive by post.

#### How is your information used?

We may use any information obtained by telephone, e-mail, Website contact form or other media to handle customer and other enquiries, including addressing any complaints. This may include contacting you to discuss any such enquiries or complaints.

We may monitor e-mails and other electronic messages for security reasons. We use e-mail monitoring or blocking software (spam filters).

We may also use any personal data obtained by telephone, e-mail, Website contact form or other media to improve our internal processes, including staff training and quality control.

#### Lawful basis of processing

When we process your personal data in connection with telephone calls, e-mails or other media, we do so on the basis of our legitimate interests in responding to customer and other queries and in creating and retaining records of such communications for training purposes and for evidentiary purposes.

## How long do we retain your data?

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

## Additional Information

#### Compliance with legal obligations, etc.

We may process (including disclose) your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligations binding on us; to protect the rights, property, or safety of our staff, our customers, or others; and to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights.

When we process your personal data for the above purposes, we do so on the basis that such processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject or necessary in order to protect the vital interests of a natural person, respectively or necessary in order to pursue our legitimate interests in exercising our legal rights.

#### Corporate governance

We may share your personal data with any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006.

We may disclose your personal data to third parties:

in the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may if relevant disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets; or

if we or substantially all of our assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by us about our customers will be one of the transferred assets.

When we process your personal data for the above purposes, we do so on the basis that we have a legitimate interest in pursuing business aims and objectives.

## Data transfers

We do not transfer personal data outside of the European Economic Area except with regard to any emails you send to us which are processed and held within the United States by Help Scout Inc. Help Scout Inc. complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union to the United States. Help Scout Inc. has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles.

## Data Security

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

## Your rights

#### Your personal data is protected by legal rights, which include your rights:

**Request access to your personal data** (commonly known as a "data subject access request"). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.

**Request correction of the personal data that we hold about you**. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.

**Request erasure of your personal data**. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.

**Object to processing** **of your personal data** where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.

**Request restriction of processing of your personal data**. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data's accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.

**Request the transfer of your personal data to you or to a third party**. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.

**Withdraw consent at any time** **where we are relying on consent to process your personal data**. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

If you want to exercise any of these rights, please contact us using the details above.

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact us at using the details above. If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

You also have the right to complain to the Information Commissioner's Office, which regulates the processing of personal data, about how we are processing your personal data.
